I swear,
these Republican spies are such pushovers.
But this guy will be different...
Ten days go by fast...
Teach, you're back!
I haven't seen you in forever!
Nor I you.
You were off vacationing in the Lylat Kingdom, right?
You lucky dog.
I hear their seafood is to die for.
I had a pretty good time.
How was your break?
Oh, it was a blast.
And I bought souvenirs,
so you should come over to the dining room!
I timed the food to be ready
right when you got back.
I hope you like it.
That does smell nice.
By the way, where are the others?
They haven't gotten back from their vacations yet.
Slackers, the lot of 'em.
Of course, that was all a load of lies.
Figures.
Damn it, I figured that even the mighty
Klaus would let his guard down
after having just come back from a vacation.
It'll take more than that to make
a first-rate spy slip up.
You've improved a lot,
but you still have a long way to go.
If you're gonna browbeat us,
at least teach us how to do it right next time!
Conduct your surprise attacks floatily.
That concludes the lesson.
You haven't improved one bit, Teach!
Still, your enthusiasm came across loud and clear.
Magnificent.
We're all fired up and ready to go.
After all, Lamplight's been promoted from a
provisional team to an actual team.
I'm ready to do my best on our first official mission!
I've got all my ducks in a row, yo!
It's time for us to put our unity to the test!
Your passion is all well and good
but our first official mission is already done.
I finished three missions in the Lylat Kingdom,
as well as another two domestically.
The next mission's going to be our sixth one.
What the heck?!
SPY CLASSROOM
MISSION: Daughter Dearest I
You completed these on your own?
In that tiny time frame?
I find that hard to believe,
but I guess I should know better than to doubt you.
That said, we went out of our way to get
the girls formally registered.
Why didn't you bring them with you to Lylat?
They need more training.
They're talented, I'll give them that.
But they aren't ready yet.
The only reason I brought them along
last time was because
it was the only way I could fool Guido.
At this rate, you'll end up leaving them
rotting on the bench for years.
You act like that's a foregone conclusion.
It's a mistake you seem all too liable to make.
I'd like to take a sabbatical from missions for a while.
Surely that last set I completed must have
bought us some breathing room.
I want to gather up whatever intel I can on Serpent.
You know full well that that isn't an option.
Even as we speak,
the Empire is defiling our borders by
sending villainous spies across them.
Stopping them is costing our countrymen their lives.
Losing Inferno cost our nation dearly.
In particular, this mission is one
that only you can complete.
You're refusing to do it?
I memorized the whole thing.
What choice do I have but to accept it?
It's the only way I can protect the masses
that Inferno so loved.
I brought you some tea, Boss.
As I've told you a million times,
please stop calling me that.
Those are some excellent leaves.
They must have been expensive.
Their fragrance caught my attention
while I was out on vacation.
I didn't want to serve you anything but the best.
I don't get it.
What did I do to inspire such affection from her?
How beautiful.
This was a bold attempt at seduction.
I commend your bravery.
Boss...
Is that not what this is?
Forgive me.
Looking back, it still doesn't make sense.
I didn't do anything to deserve such fondness.
You didn't make it back until quite late today.
Do you think you'll be able to take it easier tomorrow?
It's unlikely.
I just took on a big mission,
and I got ordered to rewrite my mission reports, too.
When I wrote, "Somehow or other, I got it done,"
I got told to quit screwing around.
Boss...
Yes?
If it's all right with you,
I'd like to hold you to my bosom.
Why would that be all right with me?
There's no need to be so bashful.
Please, don't hesitate to let me dote on you.
Just for the record,
is this you practicing your seduction?
Oh no!
Boss, I promise I'm not trying to deceive you here.
All I want is for you to take a break.
What?
We succeeded in the last Impossible Mission
largely on the back of your efforts.
And even now,
you're completing missions, doing admin work,
and teaching us all on your own.
I appreciate the concern,
but you should just be focusing on your training.
For now, that means attacking me.
You mean, you want me to make a move on you?!
Grete,
the next time you come to my room,
you had better bring one of the others along with you.
B-but that's bigamy!
Thea must have been putting
ideas in her head again.
I feel oddly tired.
I guess the fatigue's catching up to me.
Make sure you protect 'em this time.
I don't have time to spend worrying about myself.
I need to prioritize the girls' safety.
An assassin hunt,
that's your next mission.
Politicians from anti-Imperial parties
across the world have been dying left and right.
They leave notes intimating they've committed suicide,
but odds of the notes being forgeries are high.
An assassin named Corpse,
who resembles a cadaver...
You're saying this is their handiwork?
That's right, two weeks ago,
a politician jumped to their death right here in Din.
In all likelihood, that too was Corpse's doing.
Our agent who got ahold of that intel was killed.
Everyone we sent to take over for them was killed, too.
In short, it's been classified as an Impossible Mission.
It sounds like this is going to be even harder
than the last Impossible Mission.
As you're aware, the Empire knows your personal intel.
If you make any overt moves,
Corpse will likely go to ground.
Take the girls along with you.
You won't be able to do this one alone.
But if I do that, Corpse could easily kill them.
I need to handle this one on my own.
Before you get into it, though,
I have another mission I need you to handle.
That scheming codger...
That didn't even make for decent sport.
I take it this was you, Lily?
Y-you spotted it?
But I set the trap so you'd run into it
after you let your guard down.
It was too obvious a trick.
Skilled spies are sensitive to hostility.
Even someone a fair bit weaker than me
would have sensed it.
Dang, and I thought I'd come so far.
Have you at least stopped forgetting
to carry your antidote?
I'll have you know that I remember it
nine times out of ten these days!
That's still not great.
Actually, while I have you, could you follow me?
Huh? What for?
Wait, you're just going to leave us here?!
Ooh, is this one of those joyride dates
Do you all want to participate in missions?
I've heard so much about?
I'm just asking for reference.
Of course we want in.
With the big caveat that we really
don't want to die, mind you.
We've all be putting a lot into our training.
I want to become a spy feared the world over
and have loads of people fawn over me.
I see.
And plus, we make less money if we're not working.
You don't have anything to worry about on that front.
Even when I complete the missions solo,
I've been splitting the completion bonuses
evenly with the team.
In that case, I'm totally down to keep playing hooky-
What happened to wanting to be fawned over?
If I can make loads of money, get treated
like an expert spy, and be revered
all for doing nothing and sleeping in,
that's basically the dream!
You're letting your greed show.
But if that's not an option,
then I really do want to take on missions.
We're still spies, you know.
All of us want to change the world.
Magnificent.
We'll continue this conversation
after the mission's over.
Wait, I get to join in on an operation already?
That's right.
I need you to spend an hour walking around town,
then buy some drinks and come back to the car.
Roger that.
Then what?
Then, we go home.
I can deal with the target on my own.
That's not a mission, that's just a shopping trip!
Ah, I've been expecting you.
Come on in.
Do you have any collaborators in the city?
You don't.
That's a relief.
How did you know I was coming?
If I had to guess...
All that's left is to head back
and write up my report.
A blown tire?
But I'm sure what I heard was a gunshot.
MISSION: Daughter Dearest I
Lily!
I'm fine, Teach!
Go west! It was a man in a beige coat!
Got it.
Did he have allies after all?
I screwed up.
He got away?
No, something is off.
Oh hey, Teach.
What happened to the bad guy?
I'm sorry.
He gave me the slip.
Wait, he really lost you?
What, feeling disillusioned?
No, no.
It's just, you sounded so confident
when you went after him,
so I'm a little surprised.
I did?
Well, we can worry about the attack later.
For now, we need to get that arm treated.
Ah, right.
Here ya go!
Why...
I'm just following your orders.
"Put on that bandage,
and once I get back, stab me with your poison
needle to numb my pain," you said.
What pain?
I mean, your arm was bleeding all over place.
My arm?
But that doesn't make any sense.
Magnificent.
There were two of each of us.
In other words, the wounded Lily I saw at first
and the Lily who stabbed me when I came back
were two different people.
And the me who ordered you to stab me
and the me you actually stabbed with your needle
were different people as well.
What's going on?
It's a trick based around disguises.
And there's only one person that could
pull a stunt like that off.
Just as I expected.
Whaaat?
You're sensitive to traps, Boss.
You always pick up on our malice and hostility.
That's why I tricked Lily and got her
to stab you out of goodwill.
I'm code name Daughter Dearest.
Now, let's fill this time with laughter and tears.
I just nicked it.
If you're lookin' for Lily's antidote,
I've got it right here.
Huh? But when?!
I never thought it'd go so smooth.
It stings to admit,
but Grete's plans really are top-notch.
I was blown away, yo.
Uh, and why wasn't I told any of this?
If we let you know ahead of time,
that information would have
made its way to the boss.
Yeah, I guess I can't really argue with that.
We finally cornered you.
There's something quite enchanting about
seeing you down on your hands and knees.
I never knew you had such a sadistic side to you.
Boss...
You've been pushing yourself too hard.
If you were in peak form,
you would have seen through my disguise
the moment you saw Lily injured like that.
You've accomplished a lot since losing Inferno.
Even just now, you worked through your vacation
to make up for our inexperience.
That sounds about right.
When was the last time you took a proper day off?
Four hundred and sixty-five days ago.
You're being rash.
A schedule like that would have had anyone else
coughing up blood and keeling over by now.
We want you to rely on us more.
We want you to be able to rest easy.
You don't have to bear it all on your own.
You have us now.
Now, about that surrender declaration...
I understand how you feel.
That's wonderful!
You're right, I am exhausted.
I'm tired to the bone.
Exactly, and that's why-
But the question is,
how much longer should I keep
playing along with this game?
Magnificent.
That poison needle devoid of malice
was a thing of beauty.
I applaud the ingenuity.
Isn't he supposed to be poisoned?
Sorry, I wasn't able to get a clean hit.
I scratched him, so I was able to
poison him a little bit, but that was it.
But how?
There's no way you should have been able
to predict the attack.
Sure there was.
Your goodwill attack was effective,
don't get me wrong.
But with how suspicious the leadup was,
I was already on high alert.
How did you see it coming?
The way you cleared the area was too blatant.
You distracted the cops and civilians from the gunshot
by covering it up with a popped tire.
It was too well-executed to just be a coincidence.
I could tell it was a trap
designed to catch someone who could recognize
the difference between the two sounds.
Once I realized I was clearly being baited,
it made me be cautious.
The spy I caught today had a similar realization.
When he discovered that both his neighbors had gone
on vacation at the same time, he got suspicious.
Our Foreign Intelligence Office did
a sloppy job clearing the area.
You all have magnificent talents,
and someday, they'll come into bloom.
At present, though, you don't have what it takes.
If I'd delegated today's mission to you,
you would have gotten killed.
I can't afford to rely on you.
I thought I was doing a better job
gauging my own stamina.
This is pathetic.
I don't have my Inferno teammates anymore.
I have to keep this up,
no matter how much it eats away at me...
Grete...
I took the liberty of making you some
herbal tea to help you sleep,
but I fear I ended up waking you up instead.
Don't worry about it.
Thank you for taking part in
our training exercise this afternoon.
We just finished up our postmortem.
Now, once you exchange an embrace with me,
the day will be perfect.
I'm going to ask you this straight.
Are you in love with me?
N-nothing gets past you, Boss.
I'm impressed you noticed.
You were trying to hide it?
Grete, as far as your feelings go, I-
Please...
don't give me your answer yet.
My heart isn't ready.
I'd really like to make my position clear.
But...
Forgive me.
Another time, then.
Thank you for that.
Could I at least give you this report for
the mission you completed today?
You ghostwrote it for me?
I did.
I figured that if I observed you,
I could at least write down the parts I saw.
Ah, so I had a guardian angel that whole time.
Does this make you want to let me dote on you?
I'm going to ignore that question,
but I really do appreciate it.
Thank you.
Wait, hold on.
I didn't tell a soul about my mission today,
and when I chose to take Lily along,
it was a spur-of-the-moment whim.
Yet in spite of that, you observed
the whole thing from start to finish
while still finding time to lead the others
and set the stage for them to launch an attack on me.
The timeline was too fast.
When did you have time to come up with that plan?
That's a fair question.
It's true that I didn't know about your mission,
so once I noticed that the homing device
I planted on Lily started moving,
the amount of time I spent after
predicting your destination,
catching a train, and figuring out the situation...
was two seconds.
That's how long the plan took me to put together.
It's really nothing all that praiseworthy.
All I did was take one
of the hundreds and thousands of mental simulations
I ran in advance and put it to the test.
You really went that far?
Of course.
The man I care about is running himself ragged
and refusing to accept my help.
I can't help but feel frustrated.
My powerlessness is making me
a burden for my beloved.
Grete, I've never once thought of you as a burden.
I'm going on an assassin hunt.
That's the next mission.
Will you lend me your strength, Grete?
I need you.
Could that be...
What?
...a proposal?
It was not.
I was joking.
It would be my pleasure to help.
I would do anything to assist you
and the team you built.
Magnificent.
Just as I expected.
For this mission, I need to select some members.
What do you mean?
I'm going to take the assassin on
with Lamplight's four strongest members by my side.